shoptiques.com 2019-11-12

# Privacy Policy — Shoptiques

Shoptiques is committed to protecting your privacy. The information collected from our Site helps us better understand our market and consumer interests. This allows us to serve our customers with the level of satisfaction they deserve. If you have questions or suggestions regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please send an email message to [privacy@shoptiques.com](mailto:privacy@shoptiques.com). Shoptiques, Inc. will only use your data to improve your experience with us. We will protect your data.

  1. **Protecting Your Privacy:** At Shoptiques, we are 100% committed to protecting the privacy and security of all of our customers and site visitors. We appreciate and respect how important privacy is. If you have any questions about how we protect your privacy, contact us at [privacy@shoptiques.com](mailto:privacy@shoptiques.com). For all our services, the data controller (the company that’s responsible for your privacy) is Shoptiques, Inc. 
  2. **How we use your information:** We use your information in a number of different ways — what we do depends on the information. The tables below set this out in detail: 

**Your name and contact details**

How we use your name & contact details | Why?  
---|---  
Deliver your purchases to you | We need this information to deliver your products to you  
Send you service messages by text, e-mail or through our app, such as order updates | We need to be able to communicate with you regarding important updates like Order Information, Shipping Tracking details, etc   
Sending you information by email, text, or mail, about our new products and services | To keep you up to date. We only send this with your permission  
Fraud prevention and detection | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Shoptiques.com – unfortunate, but absolutely essential  
Showing you Shoptiques.com advertisements as your browse the web | So you can see our latest products and deals  
Finding out what you, and other customers, like | To ensure we are giving you what you want, and to stay ahead of the competition  
  
**Your date of birth information**

How we use your date of birth | Why?  
---|---  
Birthday promotions | To celebrate your birthday with an additional discount  
Fraud prevention and detection | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Shoptiques.com – unfortunate, but absolutely essential  
  
**Your payment information (This means your card’s security/CVV code)**

How we use your payment information | Why?  
---|---  
Take payment, and give refunds | We need to collect this information to process transactions and deliver our awesome! products to you! We do not store your credit card information. [Stripe](https://www.stripe.com/), our credit card processing partner, stores all of the credit card information securely!  
Fraud prevention and detection | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Shoptiques.com – unfortunate, but absolutely essential  
  
**Your contact history with us**

How we use your contact history | Why?  
---|---  
Provide customer service and support | You expect the best service from us and we want to deliver  
Train our staff | So you get the best possible customer service  
  
**Purchase history and saved items**

How we use your purchase history and saved items | Why?  
---|---  
Sell you things | That’s the business we are in  
Provide customer service and support, and handle returns | This is what you have come to expect from us  
Finding out what you and other customers like | To ensure we are giving you what you want and to stay ahead of the competition  
  
**Information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our websites and apps**

How we use information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our websites and apps | Why?  
---|---  
Improve our website and set default options for you (such as language and currency) | To give you the best possible shopping experience  
Protect our website | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or Shoptiques.com and to meet our legal obligations about looking after your data  
  
**Information from accounts you link to us - What we do if you link your Facebook account to us**

How we use information from accounts you link to us | Why?  
---|---  
To enable you to log into our website simply and easily without having to create a specific account | To make it easier for you to use Shoptiques.com and purchase those items you want  
To provide product recommendations | So you can quickly spot things which you like  
  
**Your responses to surveys, competitions and promotions**

How we use your responses to surveys, competitions and promotions | Why?  
---|---  
Run the survey, competition or promotion | We need to use this information to select a winner. If we can’t use your entry, you can’t possibly win!  
  
You don’t have to give us any of this personal information! If you don’t provide this information, however, you may not be able to buy from the site, and you are unlikely to receive our best customer experience. But that is your choice and we respect that. We also anonymize and aggregate personal information (so that it does not identify you) and use it for purposes including testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our site and app, and developing new products and services. We also share this information with third parties.

  3. **Sharing your information:** We do not, and will not, sell any of your personal data to any third party, including your name, address, email address or credit card information. We want to earn and maintain your trust, and we believe this is absolutely essential in order do that. However, we share your data with the following categories of companies as an essential part of being able to provide our services to you, as set out in this statement: companies in the Shoptiques, Inc. group, such as the boutiques that are on our platform, as sometimes different bits of our group are responsible for different activities; companies that do things to get your purchases to you, such as payment service providers, warehouses, order packers, and delivery companies; professional service providers, such as marketing agencies, advertising partners and website hosts, who help us run our business; credit reference agencies, law enforcement and fraud prevention agencies, companies approved by you, such as social media sites, marketplace sellers and Stripe or PayPal. We may provide third parties with aggregated but anonymized information and analytics about our customers and, before we do so, we will make sure that it does not identify you. 
  4. **How we use your information:** If you have said we can, we’ll send you marketing messages by email or SMS (short message service), to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products.
  5. **How to stop marketing messages from Shoptiques.com:** through your account settings by clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email or by contacting our customer service at [support@shoptiques.com](mailto:support@shoptiques.com). Once you do this, we will update your profile to ensure that you don’t receive further marketing messages. Please note that as Shoptiques comprises a complex web of many inter-connecting services, it might take a few days for all our systems to be updated, so you might get messages from us while we process your request. Stopping marketing messages will not stop service communications.
  6. **Seeing advertisements for Shoptiques.com online:** We also engage in online advertising, also to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products. Like many other companies we target Shoptiques (& Shopkids) banners and ads to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks. The banners and ads you see will be based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of Shoptiques (or Shopkids) (for example, your Shoptiques search history, and the content you read on Shoptiques) or on Shoptiques banners or ads you have previously clicked on.
  7. **Your information and countries outside Europe:** The USA is not a country in respect of which there is a European Commission decision of adequacy, and we protect your privacy and your rights through the use of the European Commission’s standard data protection clauses. More information about these is available here http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087.
  8. **Keeping your information:** We’ll hold on to your information for as long as you have your account, or as long as is needed to be able to provide the services to you, or (in the case of any contact you may have with our customer service team) for as long as is necessary to provide support-related reporting and trend analysis only. If reasonably necessary or required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions, we may also keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account, or it is no longer needed to provide the services to you.
  9. **Your rights:** You have a lot of rights relating to your personal information: the right to be informed about how your personal information is being used; the right to access the personal information we hold about you; the right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you; the right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances; the right to stop direct marketing messages and to withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time; the right to request we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider; the right to complain to your data protection regulator; if you want to exercise your rights, have a complaint, or just have questions, please contact us at [support@shoptiques.com](mailto:support@shoptiques.com) or [privacy@shoptiques.com](mailto:privacy@shoptiques.com)
  10. **Changes to how we Protect Your Privacy:** We may change this page from time to time, to reflect how we are processing your data. If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on Shoptiques.com, Shopkids.com or other Shoptiques services, or by some other means of contact such as email, so that you are able to review the changes before you continue to use Shoptiques, Inc properties.
  11. **What about cookies?:** We use cookies when you visit our site. There are four main types of cookies: (1) Site functionality cookies – these cookies allow you to navigate the site and use our features, such as “Add to Bag” and “Lovebox”; (2) Site analytics cookies – these cookies allow us to measure and analyze how our customers use the site, to improve both its functionality and your shopping experience; (3) Customer preference cookies – when you are browsing or shopping on Shoptiques.com, these cookies will remember your preferences (like your language or location), so we can make your shopping experience as seamless as possible, and more personal to you; (4) Targeting or advertising cookies – these cookies are used to deliver ads relevant to you. They also limit the number of times that you see an ad and help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. By using our site, you agree to us placing these sorts of cookies on your device and accessing them when you visit the site in the future.
  12. **Legal Purchase Age:** If you are under 18, we require that you inform a parent or guardian about Shoptiques Inc.’s Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions as well as requiring their consent to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions before registering with Shoptiques.com or placing an order with Shoptiques.com.
  13. **International Data Transfer:** Shoptiques is a global organization, and some of your data may be transferred internationally. Although data protection laws of various countries may differ from your own, we will take appropriate steps to ensure that your personal information is handled as described in this statement and in accordance with the law.
  14. **Your California Privacy Rights:** As provided by California Civil Code Section 1798.83, a California resident who has provided Personal Information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes ("California customer") is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed Personal Information to any third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. In general, if the business has made such a disclosure of Personal Information, upon receipt of a request by a California customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom Personal Information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of Personal Information that were disclosed. However, under the law, a business is not required to provide the above-described lists if the business adopts and discloses to the public (in its privacy policy) a policy of not disclosing customer's Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Rather, the business may comply with the law by notifying the customer of his or her right to prevent disclosure of Personal Information and providing a cost free means to exercise that right. Except as expressly stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not share information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you affirmatively agree to such disclosure -- typically by opting in to receive information from a third party that is participating in some activity describes on our site. If you do ask us to share your information with a third party for its marketing purposes, we will only share information in connection with that specific activity, as we do not share information with any third party on a continual basis. To prevent disclosure of your Personal Information for use in direct marketing by a third party, do not opt in to such use when you provide Personal Information on our site. Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as we have no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information. California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by emailing [CaliforniaPrivacy@shoptiques.com](mailto:CaliforniaPrivacy@shoptiques.com). Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address.
  15. **Business Transfer:** In the event that Shoptiques, Inc., any entity or business unit in the Shoptiques Inc. group of companies, or any of their assets, are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of an acquisition, merger, sale, reorganization, consolidation or liquidation, your personal information may be one of the transferred assets. The terms of this Privacy Policy will continue to apply to your Personal Information that is transferred to the new entity.
  16. **Modification and Notification of Changes:** Shoptiques, Inc. may at our sole discretion edit this Privacy Policy. If, and only if, we make a material modification to this Privacy Policy, it will notify you as follows:   
a. sending an email to the address associated with your account. Shoptiques, Inc. is not responsible for your failure to receive an email due to the actions of your ISP or any email filtering service; therefore, you should add shoptiques.com to the list of domains approved to send you email (commonly known as your "whitelist"); and   
b. displaying a prominent announcement above the text of this Privacy Policy for thirty (30) days, with (i) and (ii) being deemed sufficient notification, of such changes. After notice of a modification to the Privacy Policy has been posted for 30 days, the notice will be removed and a brief description of the modification and the date that it went into effect will be placed in the Historical Modifications section at the end of the Privacy Policy. If you have not used the Site for more than 30 days, you should check Privacy Policy prior to any further use of the Site. Should you wish to terminate your account due to a modification to the Privacy Policy, you may do so by sending an email with the subject line "Termination" to the following email address: support@shoptiques.com. If you choose to continue using the Site, you agree that by doing so you will be deemed to accept the new Privacy Policy, as relevant.
  17. **Your consent:** By visiting shoptiques.com and/or shopkids.com, or downloading our apps: Shoptiques and/or Shopkids on the AppStore, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions.
  18. **Historical Modifications:**   
10/1/2011 Original Privacy Policy Posted.   
5/24/18 This Current Version Posted. 
  19. **How to contact us:** We always want to hear from our customers (especially if you feel we’ve let you down or could do better). If you have any questions or feedback about this notice, or would like us to stop using your information, or want to exercise any of your rights as set out above or have a complaint please don’t hesitate to contact our customer service team at [support@shoptiques.com](mailto:support@shoptiques.com), who will be happy to answer any questions you may have. You can contact our privacy team by dropping us a line at [privacy@shoptiques.com](mailto:privacy@shoptiques.com). Or if you’d like to, you can write to us at: Shoptiques, Inc., 41 East 11th Street 11th Floor New York, NY 10003, Attn: Chief Operating Officer or Chief Executive Officer.
